<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A true narrative of the late design of the papists to charge their horrid plot upon the Protestants by endeavouring to corrupt Capt. Bury and Mr. Brooks of Dublin, and to take off the evidence of Mr. Oats and Mr. Bedlow &amp;c. : as appears by the depositions taken before the Right Honourable Sir Joseph Williamson, Knight, one of His Majesties late principal secretaries of state, and the several examinations before Sir William Waller, Knight, one of His Majesties justice of the peace / published for general information.</title>
            <author>Bury, John, 17th cent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1679</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 43 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A30682</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B6216</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30876</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11675274</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11675274</idno>
            <idno type="VID">48091</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A30682)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 48091)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1481:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A true narrative of the late design of the papists to charge their horrid plot upon the Protestants by endeavouring to corrupt Capt. Bury and Mr. Brooks of Dublin, and to take off the evidence of Mr. Oats and Mr. Bedlow &amp;c. : as appears by the depositions taken before the Right Honourable Sir Joseph Williamson, Knight, one of His Majesties late principal secretaries of state, and the several examinations before Sir William Waller, Knight, one of His Majesties justice of the peace / published for general information.</title>
                  <author>Bury, John, 17th cent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Reprinted at Dublin,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Dublin] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1679.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages stained and faded, with print showthrough and loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Popish Plot, 1678.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Charles II, 1660-1685.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:48091:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A True Narrative Of the Late DESIGN Of the <hi>PAPISTS</hi> to charge their Horrid PLOT UPON THE PROTESTANTS.</p>
            <p>By endeavouring to corrupt Capt. BURY and Mr. BROOKS of <hi>Dublin;</hi> and to take off the Evidence of Mr. OATS and Mr. BEDLOW, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>As appears by the Depoſitions taken before the Right Honourable Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> Knight, one of His Majeſties late Principal Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretaries of State; And the ſeveral <hi>Examinations</hi> before Sir <hi>William Waller,</hi> Knight, One of His Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Publiſhed for General Information.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Reprinted at DUBLIN, 1679.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="approbation">
            <pb facs="tcp:48091:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THIS <hi>Narrative</hi> of the late Deſign of the Papiſts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Publiſhed for general Information, <hi>doth exactly agree with the Examinations taken by Sir</hi> Joſeph Williamſon <hi>and myſelf.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>WILLIAM WALLER.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>March the</hi> 29th. — 79.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="depositions">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:48091:2"/>
            <head>The DEPOSITIONS of CAPTAIN BURY.</head>
            <div type="deposition">
               <p>ON the 11th of this Inſtant <hi>January,</hi> I received the annexed Note from Mr. <hi>James Nettervile,</hi> on the 13th I went to him; as ſoon as I came, he told me, he had ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing to impart to me in private; We went into a Room alone, and he asked me If I did not here that there were perſons making inquiry to find out ſome that would amuſe thoſe that had impeached the Lords, and thoſe concerned about the Plot. I told him I heard nothing of it. He told me there were ſuch, and that I ſhould find the Game would turn another way; and that I might do my ſelf a kindneſs, if I pleaſed. I told him my affairs called me for <hi>Ireland,</hi> that I muſt be gone on the <hi>Thurſday</hi> following. He told me it would be worth my while to ſtays and asked me if I could nor prove that one Mr. <hi>Digby</hi> had meetings With Mr. <hi>Oats</hi> and Mr. <hi>Bedlow.</hi> I told him no, for he knew there had been no great friendſhip of late betwixt us (this I lookt upon as an introduction to the deſign); but he came cloſe to me, and told me, a perſon had been with him con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning this matter, and that indeed they had a jealouſie of Mr. <hi>Blood;</hi> and if I would diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover any thing of that nature againſt him, I ſhould have 4 or 500<hi>l.</hi> for my pains. To this I ſeemed to hearken (but was much ſurpriſed at this unexpected diſcourſe) and did plainly ſee their deſign was to turn the Game another way, as he ſaid before. I did not diſcourage him, but told him I would conſider of it; and if I did not go on <hi>Thurſday,</hi> I would ſee him again; and that he knew well I was very hard to believe this plot; and then he told me that he could bring a priſoner in that place to drink a pot of Ale with me, that could give me an account what a Rogue Mr. <hi>Bedlow</hi> was; but I being in haſte, took my leave of him, he injoyning me to ſecreſie. At my return <hi>I</hi> could not meet with Mr. <hi>Blood,</hi> but haveing ſome buſineſs with Sir <hi>Ralph Dalaval,</hi> and the Lady <hi>Elizabeth</hi> his Daughter, and being full with this deviliſh deſign, I told the ſtory to them, and ſaid, when I was in <hi>Ireland,</hi> I ſhould hear, and they ſhould find that this was the Game they intended to play, To turn the plot from themſelves, and doubted not they would find ſome to carry it on.</p>
               <p>On the 14th (in the morning) I went to Mr. <hi>Bloods</hi> houſe, and acquainted him with it; he deſired me to meet him in the evening, becauſe he deſired to conſider of it; but told me then, he had no reaſon to flight it, becauſe the morning before, a Knight [Sir <hi>Thomas Longvile</hi>] had been with him, and told him there was a deſign againſt him of the ſame kind, and deſired him to inquire after it.</p>
               <p>In the evening <hi>I</hi> met with Mr. <hi>Blood,</hi> who deſired me to keep my correſpondence with the ſaid <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and to know or him how <hi>I</hi> ſhould be ſecured my payments, and what it was they would have me do.</p>
               <p>On the 16th. I went accordingly to him, and told him I had conſidered of what we had diſcourſed before, and had ſtopt my Journey as to that day; he was very glad to ſee me, and told me, that the party <hi>[Ruſſel]</hi> had been with him again about the buſineſs, and I might get 500<hi>l</hi> without any prejudice to my ſelf, I told him that Money would do me a great kindneſs at this time (for he knew I had waited a long time here, and that it was very
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:48091:3"/> hard with me), therefore deſired to know what they would have me to do, and how I ſhould be ſure of the 500 <hi>l,</hi> for I expected it ſhould be a perſon of good credit that would lay down the 500<hi>l.</hi> He told me I ſhould not need to queſtion that, for they were of credit enough. But he that came to him <hi>[Ruſſel],</hi> was only imployed to pay the Money; and if <hi>I</hi> ſhall tell him that you will do the buſineſs, you ſhall be ſure of the money; not ſo, ſaid I, Firſt let me know what it is diſtinctly, and how I ſhall be ſure of the 500<hi>l.</hi> or <hi>I</hi> will not ſtir a foot in it, but begon on <hi>Monday.</hi> Saith he, Would you have the money before-hand? then it may be you will not do it. No, ſaid I, that I do not deſire. But will you depoſite it in a third hand? Truly, ſaid he, that is very fair, and I doubt not but they will do it (for I told him none was betten able to carry it on than you; for <hi>Mr. Blood</hi>'s man was formerly your Servant, and preferred by you to him) and told me, that on <hi>Saturday</hi> by two or three of the Clock, his friend would be with him again; but that he would be ſhy of diſcourſing with me; and deſired that <hi>I</hi> would come to him <hi>[Ruſſel]</hi> on <hi>Munday,</hi> and then I ſhould underſtand more. Upon my return I acquainted <hi>Mr. Blood</hi> with the whole diſcourſe, and that I was to leave the town on <hi>Munday,</hi> haveing ſtayed my utmoſt time, becauſe I had a Suit depending in Chancery, at <hi>Dublin;</hi> and that if I were not there the beginning of the <hi>Term,</hi> it would be great damage to me, becauſe my abſence would be looked upon as a contempt; but <hi>Mr. Blood</hi> requeſted me to ſtay untill he had acquainted His Majeſty, or one of his Secretaries with it, to know his pleaſure as to my going or ſtay.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>John Bury.</signed>
                  <dateline>Sworn before me <date>the 17 of <hi>Jan.</hi> 1678.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>J. Williamſon.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="deposition">
               <p>
                  <hi>SAturday</hi> the 18th of <hi>January,</hi> I was with <hi>James Nettervile</hi> in the Evening; he told me his Freind <hi>[Ruſſel]</hi> had left him about half an hour before I came, and that he acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted him with what I propounded (to wit) that 500<hi>l.</hi> ſhould be depoſited in a third per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons hand; and he told me his friend was contented it ſhould be ſo, and thought it but reaſonable, and therefore was willing to put it into a Goldſmiths hand I asked him if they had conſidered the method we ſhould carry this on? and whether they had drawn up the heads of what I was to ſwear? He told me, no; but his Friend would be with him again upon <hi>Wedneſday,</hi> and that all things ſhould be prepared and ready for me by <hi>Thurſday</hi> Morning. I asked him if it would be convenient for me to meet his Friend? He told me not as yet, for he was very wary, ſhy, and fearful of being betrayed. I told him I thought my meeting with him was not material; only, ſaid I, let him be ſure to ſecure the money, and he needs not doubt of effecting the buſineſs. But, ſaid <hi>I,</hi> 500 <hi>l.</hi> is not all that I ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect from him for this ſervice, that is but a melting Caſh, and I have a great Charge, and a Wife and ſix Children, and you know I have lyen a long time waiting here, almoſt to my utter ruin, and have been very hardly dealt with. Now, if I accompliſh this, I ſhall loſe my intereſt in all other parties, and therfore expect he ſhould make me a very good intereſt with that party. Never fear that, ſaid he, you ſhall have intereſt enough with them; and if we can but turn off this Plot, there is no danger of effecting our buſineſs; for, ſaith he, the King will believe nothing of it. Well ſaid <hi>I,</hi> I muſt truſt to you to make my intereſt; but I part<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſee how things are like to go, and think it wiſdom to come in with the beginning of the Game. Saith he (ſwearing by his Maker) Never fear, if we turn off this Plot, we do our buſineſs, and you will be made for ever. But, ſaid I, Why will you defer this while <hi>Wedneſday?</hi> That is a great while, and delayes are not good. Said he, I did not expect you till <hi>Sunday:</hi> But if I hear any thing in the mean time, I will write to you, and it ſhall be left at Mr. <hi>Brooke's</hi> Lodging. I hear, ſaid I, the Parliament is Prorogued; and that is true e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:48091:3" rendition="simple:additions"/> ſaid he; and till they meet again, we can receive no great damage <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> hear the Apprentices are ready to riſe and pull down <hi>Newgate.</hi> Said I, then I ſuppoſe that is, becauſe the men <hi>[Jeſuits]</hi> are not executed. What elſe, ſaid he? and that is our great danger; that the people ſhould run into a Rebellion before we accompliſh our buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs. I asked him if he had taken an abſtract, as he ſaid he would, of what that man in the priſon could ſwear, to take off Mr. <hi>Bedlow</hi>'s Evidence. I have not yet, ſaid he, but we are ſure enough of him, and ſhall make <hi>Bedlow</hi> Rogue enough. Pray, ſaid I, what will he ſwear? That the very morning the Proclamation came forth concerning Sir <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mondbury Godfrey,</hi> Mr. <hi>Bedlow</hi> came to his chamber, and asked him if he had ever ſeen Sir <hi>Edmundbury Godfrey:</hi> For, ſaid he, if I knew what a like man he was, I could eaſily get 500<hi>l.</hi> and however, I am reſolved to hazard my Neck, but I will have it; and that he would have had this man go with him to <hi>Somerſethouſe</hi> to ſee the Rooms, and promiſed to get him money, if he would go with him. But, ſaid I, Mr. <hi>Nettervile,</hi> it is ſaid Mr. <hi>Bedlow</hi> was out of Town before the Proclamation came out; that is not ſo, ſaith he, for this mans Wife went into the Countrey with him. A great deal of diſcourſe more we had, all tending to the incouraging of me to carry on this buſineſs, to turn this plot to be a <hi>Proteſtant Plot</hi> for the deſtruction of the <hi>Papiſts,</hi> and then I ſhould be made for ever. When I paid the Reckoning, and was coming away, ſaid he, you will always come to your charge, but I hope the end will pay for all.</p>
               <p>On <hi>Wedneſday</hi> the 22d, at Night, I went to Mr. <hi>Nettervile.</hi> expecting to have the model how they would have me Swear, and in what Goldſmiths hand they would put the 500<hi>l.</hi> But as ſoon as ever I came to him, he told me that he had been put into ſuch a fright, that he was never in all his life before; for, ſaid he, Mr. <hi>Oates,</hi> Mr, <hi>Bedlow,</hi> Sir <hi>William Waller,</hi> and another Juſtice have been with me; they called for Irons, one would have fifty pound weight, another would have an hundred pound weight put upon me. At length Sir <hi>William Waller</hi> began to examine me, and told me, he knew I could diſcover a great deal; ſo I deſired the reſt might be put out of the Room, and I confeſt all to him and the other Juſtice, they both prom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſing me my pardon. Have you confeſt all, ſaid I? how could I help it, ſaid he? I was never in ſuch a fright in all my life; and they promiſed me my par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don. What have you confeſt, ſaid I? I have told them, ſaid he, that 500<hi>l.</hi> was to be depoſited in a Goldſmiths hand, and that I had ſent for a Gentleman, and treated with him about it. Have you told them my Name, ſaid I? he pauſed at that; no, ſaid he; but I muſt tell them, but I thought firſt to acquaint you with it. Then ſaid I, it ſeems you have left me in the lurch, and have made no proviſion for me; therefore ſince it is ſo, you will give me leave to play my own Game; and ſeeing you have confeſt, let us now play our Game as well as we can on the other ſide, and be ſure to be ingenuous, and confeſs what ever we know. I will immediately to Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> and declare the whole Story. Pray do ſo, ſaith he, neglect no time, but go this night. And ſo we parted.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>John Bury.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="deposition">
               <head>The Depoſition of Alderman <hi>BROOKS.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>THat on<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> about the 23d. of <hi>December,</hi> 1678. I was at the <hi>Marſhalſeys</hi> in <hi>Southwark,</hi> where was one <hi>James Nettervile,</hi> a priſoner there for debt; who deſired me to do ſo much for him, as to carry a Note for a friend of his that was a priſoner alſo, unto one <hi>Pierce Butler,</hi> that lived in <hi>Germanſtreet,</hi> near my Lodging; and ſaid, if I would procure any of his friends to come to his friend there, he would have money enough, whereof he
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:48091:4"/> ſhould have a ſhare; and alſo it would be a great kindneſs to him; whereupon I told him I would, provided he would write it quickly. Whereupon he called forth his friend, and they two conſulted together, and he wrote two or three lines, and gave them me for the ſaid <hi>Butler.</hi> But when I came to the place where I was directed they told me he was gone out of Town in obedience to the Kings Proclamation. And ſo I troubled my ſelf no fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, but put the Note in my pocket: The next morning he ſent a meſſenger to me, to know what I had done in it; I deſired him to tell the ſaid Mr. <hi>Nettervile,</hi> that the ſaid Mr. <hi>Butler</hi> was gone out of Town in obedience to his Majeſties Proclamation.</p>
               <p>About ten days after, I had occaſion for ſome waſte paper; and putting my hand in my pocket, I ſit on this Note that I ſhould have delivered to <hi>Butler,</hi> and opened it, and read it, and found in it theſe words written, or to this effect.</p>
               <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <p>Sir, I am here committed by the name of <hi>Daniel Edmonds,</hi> by a Juſtice of the Peace in the Country, as being a Recuſant. And therefore I deſire of you, that you will come unto me here, that I may adviſe with you; and in ſo doing, you will oblige your friend,</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>Dominick Kelly.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>This run in my mind, till about the 5th. inſtant at night; and then being at Mr. <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor</hi>'s Coffee-houſe at <hi>Charingcroſs,</hi> I there met with a paper, intituled, Mr. <hi>Praunces Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcovery of the Plot, and of Sir</hi> Edmondbury Godfreys <hi>murtherers;</hi> wherein (amongſt other things) there was mentioned two <hi>Iriſh</hi> Prieſts to be guilty, the one named <hi>Gerrald,</hi> and the other <hi>Kelly;</hi> whereupon it came into my mind, that the man that I carried the Note for into <hi>Germanſtreet,</hi> muſt be the ſame <hi>Kelly,</hi> becauſe by that Note he was committed by the name of <hi>Edmonds,</hi> and his name was <hi>Kelly.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The next morning being the 16th of this inſtant <hi>January</hi> (thinking to have found the ſame <hi>Kelly</hi> there), I came there; and coming to the aforeſaid <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and after ſome ſecret diſcourſe, I asked him how his friend did that I carried the Note for? he told me he procured Bail. Then I asked him what he was? he told me that he was a <hi>Prieſt,</hi> and one of thoſe that <hi>Oats</hi> (that Rogue) had impeached. I asked him how he could get Bail, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Prieſt; he told me, they did not know that he was a Prieſt; and thoſe that were his Bail, would be Bail for any for money; and he gave them ten ſhilling a piece, and the fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low that procured them, five ſhillings; and he got them the copy of his Commitment for them to move by; and the Prieſt promiſed him, the ſaid <hi>Nettervile,</hi> ſeven pounds. But he had not left it him as yet; and ſo we left this diſcourſe, and came to other.</p>
               <p>That he having ſent by me a Letter, and a petition to Mrs. <hi>Eleanor Wall,</hi> a Gentlewo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man that belongs to the Dutcheſs of <hi>Portſmouth</hi> (whom he calls Cozen), whereby to get him ſome money for his preſent ſupply: but I having no opportunity to meet with her, could give him no account of that matter; whereupon he ſaid that he was in ſuch want, that if he had not help ſpeedily, he ſhould be turned into the Common-ſide: I told him that money was ſo ſcarce with me, that I could not lend him any; but if I could, I would. Whereupon he called me aſide into the corner of the Yard, by the Gate, and told me That if I would be rul'd by him: he would put me into a way whereby we ſhould have money enough. I asked him how? he told me, if I would but joyn and aſſiſt to vilifie the Evidence of <hi>Oats</hi> and <hi>Bedlow,</hi> thoſe two Rogues; whereupon I laughed at him, and ſaid, it is impoſſible; their Evidence was grounded upon too good a foundation: he told me <hi>I</hi> was miſtaken, and I ſhould hear otherwiſe in a little while.</p>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:48091:4"/>
               <p>Upon the 17th. of <hi>January</hi> I went again to him, thinking to have gained ſomething of him, what was become of this Prieſt, but could not; and was taking my leave of him, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, I muſt go home, for I had ſome buſineſs to write for <hi>Ireland,</hi> to ſend by Captain <hi>Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry,</hi> who was to go on Monday; he told me, he believed he ſhould ſtop Captain <hi>Bury</hi>'s journey; I told him, I hoped not ſo; he anſwered, it ſhould not be to his prejudice. To which <hi>I</hi> anſwered, why then with all my heart, for I would not be againſt any thing that ſhould be for his good. And ſo there came in one <hi>Ruſſel</hi> an Iriſh man, that had ſome bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs with him. And ſo we parted.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>William Brooks.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="deposition">
               <head>The ſecond information of <hi>Mr. Brooks.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>I Being with Mr. <hi>Nettervile</hi> at the <hi>Marſhalſey</hi> in <hi>Southwark,</hi> Mr. <hi>Nettervile</hi> deſired me I would do him the kindneſs as to carry another Letter for his Friend to one Captain <hi>Kelly,</hi> who had three or four Employments in the Tower of <hi>London;</hi> I told him I would if it was any kindneſs to him. So <hi>Nettervile</hi> with <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> went together, &amp; wrote a Letter to this Capt <hi>Kelly</hi> of the Tower; the Contents were much the ſame with that I carried to <hi>Pierce Butler.</hi> I carried it to the Tower, and Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> was not at home; ſo I delivered it to his Wife. As ſoon as ſhe read it, the tears were in her eye; ſhe ſtruck her hand on her breaſt, ſaying, <hi>Alas poor man, is he taken? I was in hopes he had been ſafe, of all the reſt.</hi> She thankt me very kindly, and told me, as ſoon as her Husband came home, ſhe would give it him. When I went to Mr. <hi>Nettervile</hi> again, he thankt me for carrying the Letter for his Friend <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> to the Tower, and told me Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> had been with them, and treated them very civilly with wine and meat, and had ſpent five ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings upon them. I asked <hi>Nettervile</hi> what Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> was? He told me he was a true Iriſh man. I asked him if he was a Papiſt? He hath taken the Oaths, ſaid he; but he is a well-wiſher to us. On Thurſday the 18th. of <hi>January, Nettervile</hi> deſired me to carry a Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter from himſelf to Capt. <hi>Kelly,</hi> which Letter ſignified to him that his Friend <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> was gone, and how that he had promiſed him 7 <hi>l.</hi> to diſcharge himſelf out of the Priſon, but had not yet been ſo good as his word; therefore deſired that he would take ſome ſpeedy courſe that he may have the 7<hi>l.</hi> to d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſcharge himſelf out of <hi>Priſon:</hi> This Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter I delivered to Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi>'s own hand in the Tower. He read it, and told me he was very glad his Friend was out; but that he had never ſeen him ſince; pray, ſays he, remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber me kindly to Mr. <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and tell him, For his kindneſs to my Friend, I will do him all the ſervice I can.</p>
               <p>Upon the 28th. of <hi>January</hi> I was deſired by Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> to go to Mr. <hi>Net<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tervile,</hi> to try what more I could get out of him. On the 30th. I went to him, and told him, that I had met with Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon;</hi> and he ſeemed to be angry, and thought we had not diſcovered all we knew. And I told <hi>Nettervile,</hi> that although he had promiſe of his pardon, yet it was expected he ſhould do more for it than he had done: As for my part, ſaid I, you know I could diſcover nothing, but what diſcourſe paſſed betwixt you and I, and that I have done to the full. Therefore, if you know any more, I would adviſe you to diſcover it; for ſince you have gone thus far, I think you ought not to conceal any thing of what you know more. The Grand thing I perceive they deſire of you, and that which I think is all they can expect from you, is, That you would declare from whom the 500 <hi>l.</hi> was to come. He thankt me for my advice, and told me, that he believed <hi>Sir Joſeph Williamſon</hi> had not peruſed all his Examinations, for he had Anſwered all the Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtions
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:48091:5" rendition="simple:additions"/> they had asked him. And if they had any thing more to ask him, he would An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer them.</p>
               <p>Upon <hi>Friday</hi> the 31th of <hi>January,</hi> I acquainted Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon</hi> with what he ſaid; he ordered him to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> brought to the Council on <hi>Saturday</hi> morning, where I met him at the door, before he was called; I told him, I ſuppoſed the cheif Queſtion that would be put to him, would be, Whoſe this 500 <hi>l.</hi> was? and begged of him that he would diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover what he knew of it. Upon his coming out from the Council, I asked him if that was not the queſtion they put to him? he told me it was: I asked him what account he had given them, he told me he thought they were ſatisfied, for they were very kind to him, and promiſed him, that ſo long as they lived, he ſhould have the protection of that Board.</p>
               <p>On <hi>Tueſday,</hi> the 4th. of <hi>February</hi> following, Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon</hi> ſeeing me at the Counc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> door, called me in, and asked me if I thought I could get any more out of <hi>Net<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tervile? I</hi> tould him I thought he had given him ſatisfaction when he was before them, concerning whoſe the Money was. <hi>I</hi> told Sir <hi>Joſeph</hi> the diſcourſe I had with <hi>Nettervile,</hi> at his going into the houſe, and at his coming back; then he told me, that he had not b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>en ingenious with them, for he would confeſs nothing at firſt; but after ſome queſtions being asked in general terms, he told them that it was to come from ſome of the Lords in the Tower; and deſired me that I would go once more to ſee if I could get any thing from him</p>
               <p>The next morning the Earl of <hi>Eſſex</hi> deſired to ſpeak with me; I waited upon him at the Council-Chamber; and he deſired me alſo, that I would go to Mr. <hi>Nettervile</hi> to ſee what <hi>I</hi> could get farther from him.</p>
               <p>So on <hi>Thurſday</hi> the 6<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>h of <hi>February,</hi> I did go to Mr. <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and told him I was not come on a bare viſit, but I was commanded by the Earl of <hi>Eſsex,</hi> and Sir <hi>Joſeph VVilli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amſon</hi> (whom he knew had both been very kind to him) to adviſe him, that he would be ingenious, and diſcover what further he knew in this buſineſs. Truly, ſaid I, I ſuppoſe all they do expect from you, is, that you would make ſome clear diſcovery unto them whoſe money this 500 <hi>l.</hi> was; ſaith he (Swearing by his Soul) I did tell them all <hi>I</hi> knew, I thought they had been ſatisfied; no,, ſaid I, they are not; and Sir <hi>Joſeph VVilliamſon</hi> ſaith, you were not ingenious; for you only in general terms told them it was ſome of the Lords money in the Tower. Now if you can remember which of the Lords money it was, it may ſatisfie them; for they judg, and ſo do I, and every one elſe, that <hi>Ruſsel</hi> would as eaſily tell you whoſe it was, as to tell you it was ſome of the Lords in the Tower. I could get no more from him a great while; but after we had ſate and diſcourſed ſometime, he told me that <hi>Brewer</hi> was to be before the Council the next day, and he believed he ſhould be ſent for to<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>; I ſuppoſe not, ſaid I, unleſs I have ſome better account to give them from you: ſo juſt upon my coming away I told him; <hi>Mr. Nettervile,</hi> I am ſory I can give no better account of my Journey to you; therefore pray, if you have any thing more to ſay, let me know it before I go. After he had pauſed a wile. By my Soul, ſaid he, I cannot remember the particular name of any Lord but one. Who is that, ſaid I? my Lord <hi>Staf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford,</hi> ſaith he; but all the reſt were to contribute to it; for <hi>Ruſsel</hi> told me he was to go immediatly to the Tower, to get the Money raiſed; and that it was a difficult thing to get all the Lords together; and if he ſhould go to them apart, they might make ſcruples, and ſo delay the buſineſs; and therefore he ſhould make all the haſte he could to get the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney ready.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="relation">
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:48091:5"/>
            <head>A Relation of other Material Circumſtances and Diſcourſes, in reference to the before menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned deſign.</head>
            <p>LEſt the <hi>Jeſuitical</hi> party ſhould ſay of the following Proceedings, that they are falſe and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eigned, as their Impudence affirmeth in all other inventions of theirs, when de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tected; 'Tis neceſſary the World ſhould underſtand the occaſional circumſtances, intro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducing this helliſh attaque to be made upom this honeſt. Gentleman, Captain <hi>Bury,</hi> who for his worth and reputation is known to ſeveral perſons of Honour and good Quality in this Nation.</p>
            <p>The affairs that brought him into <hi>England,</hi> from his habitation in the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> was to Petition His Majeſty, and the Honourable Privy-Council, touching a debt due to his Father, Sir <hi>William Bury</hi> of <hi>Grantham</hi> in <hi>Lincolnſhire,</hi> deceaſed for his ſervice in being one of His Majeſties Lords Commiſſioners for managing the Government of <hi>Ireland;</hi> and in proſecution thereof, being ſeveral times in company with Mr. <hi>Netervile,</hi> who was for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly a Clerk in the Court of Claims, in <hi>Dublin,</hi> and who pretend<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d to inform the Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain of ſeveral concealed Lands and houſes in <hi>Ireland,</hi> which he might place his debt up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on; And upon the Captains receipt of his ſaid Letter of the 11th of <hi>January,</hi> 1678, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiring a ſpeedy conference with the Captain, touching matters which may redound to his advaintage, which the Captain readily embraced (ſuppoſing it referred to the ſaid con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealed Houſes and Lands); and according to <hi>Netterviles</hi> requeſt by his Note, on the ſaid 13th of <hi>January</hi> laſt, the Captain viſited the ſaid <hi>Nettervile</hi> in the <hi>Marſhalſey</hi> in <hi>Southwark;</hi> when in ſtead of a communication as to the aforeſaid concerns (the ſaid <hi>Nettervile</hi> being no ſtranger to the Captains long abode here, and the expence he had been at in his ſoli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>citation) took the opportunity to feel the Captains pulſe, as to the horrid fact before-mentioned.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Prima facie.</hi> It aſtoniſhed the honeſt Captain to think that <hi>Netterviles</hi> had diſcovered a matter of that nature to him; and conſidering if he ſhould reveal it to any one, there would be but his aſſerting it, and <hi>Netterviles</hi> denial, beſides the cenſure the World would paſs on the Captains Reputation, from the apprehenſion in <hi>Netterviles</hi> breaſt, that the Captain would be, or was fit to be profligated in ſuch a concern, which with the danger and hazard he might expoſe his life to by ſuch diſcovery, and the urgency of his particular affairs requiring his perſonal and ſpeedy attendance in <hi>Dublin</hi> (having two Conditional Decrees awarded againſt him, which would have been made abſolute this laſt <hi>Hillary-term</hi> for want of his appearance there). All theſe Conſiderations made him ſometimes reſolve within himſelf, to ſtifle the wicked propoſals of <hi>Nettervile.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But weighing the direful effects of ſuch a contrivance, which if proſecuted by ſome other Inſtruments, when he was departed this Kingdom, would not only have been the deſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of his intimate friend, and old acquaintance, Mr. <hi>Blood</hi> but prejudicial to his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtie, and the whole Kingdom, in taking off the evidence of Mr, <hi>Oats</hi> and Mr. <hi>Bedlow,</hi> and thereby the <hi>Papiſts</hi> might ſtill carry on their deviliſh deſign and Plot, when they had waſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed their own hands, and made ſuch an alteration; when the innocent would have been ruined, and the true <hi>Bloodſuckers</hi> acquitted.</p>
            <p>This Conſideration ſo affected the Captain, that he reſolved to leave the event o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his particular concerns to Providence; and as you read by his Depoſition, he repaired to Mr. <hi>Blood,</hi> and gave him intelligence thereof. And having ſo imparted the ſame to him, the goodneſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of God appeared much to the Captains ſatisfaction, touching his troubleſome thoughts about his particular concerns, by his Majeſties Gracious pleaſure, in ordering
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:48091:6"/> Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon</hi> to write to the Lord Chancellor of <hi>Ireland,</hi> that the Captain might ſuſtain no damage in his concerns, by his non-appearance there, being commanded by his Majeſtie to attend his Service here, which Letter was ſent accordingly.</p>
            <p>Upon the 17th. of <hi>January</hi> laſt, as the Captain was going to attend Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> to give in his Depoſition, meeting with Alderman <hi>Brooks,</hi> and diſcourſing with him of <hi>Net<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tervile,</hi> he told the Captain he had been at the <hi>Marſhalſeys</hi> the day before with <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and feared he had done a very ill thing; which upon the Captains enquiry what it was, the ſaid Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> was ſomewhat unwilling to acknowledg, until he had ſearcht further into it. But before their departure, Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> told the Captain, that <hi>Nettervile</hi> had pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cured Bail for one <hi>Dominick Kelly,</hi> who was one of the Murtherers of Sir <hi>Edmundbury God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frey;</hi> which Relation of the Alderman gave a confirmation to the Captain of the wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of <hi>Nettervile,</hi> and Gods Goodneſs in animating the Captain to what he was then going about, touching his own Information.</p>
            <p>Which when he had ſignified to Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> he was much affected with it, &amp; told the Captain of what great concernment it was, to have the ſaid <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> in cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody; and deſired the Captain to bring the ſaid Alderman <hi>Brooks</hi> to him; which the Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain deſired reſpite in, that Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> might make ſome further inquiry, as he ſaid he would, into the concern; and alſo leaſt the Information given by the ſaid Captain ſhould be diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered, before there was a further progreſs made for the obtaining a full diſcovery of the deſign, and perſons acting therein.</p>
            <p>Upon the [19 <hi>January] Sunday</hi> morning, <hi>Mr. Brooks</hi> came to the Captains Lodging, to know whether his Journey held for <hi>Ireland</hi> the next day; and then told the Captain he had been the day before with <hi>Nettervile;</hi> and upon the Captains demanding whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther he had learnt any thing more touchig <hi>Dominick Kelly,</hi> the ſaid Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> gave the Captain the full account, which the Captain cauſed to be put in writing, and carried him to Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> to make Oath of the ſame, which he did, which appears by his foregoing information. And the Captain could not but take notice of a Series of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidence all along in this buſineſs; for by what Alderman <hi>Brooks</hi> atteſted, <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> was ſo infatuated, as to ſend the Letter unſealed to <hi>Pierce Butler</hi> by the Alderman, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though he was in ſuch dangerous Circumſtances.</p>
            <p>Upon Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> his free acknowledgment of theſe paſſages, the Captain (deſireing his ſecreſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>) acquainted the ſaid Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> of <hi>Netterviles</hi> prank with him; which on the <hi>Monday</hi> following, Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> (being to meet Mr. <hi>Lowman</hi> and Mr. <hi>Glover,</hi> the Keeper and Clerk of the <hi>Marſhalſey,</hi> to conſider ſome way for the diſcovery of thoſe who were Bail for <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi>) happend to give ſome hints of the Captains informatiom to the ſaid Mr. <hi>Lowman,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Glover;</hi> whereby Mr <hi>Oates</hi> coming to have ſome underſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thereof, with Mr <hi>Bedlow,</hi> and by an untimely proceſs therein, going to <hi>Nettervile</hi> with Sir <hi>William Waller,</hi> ſpoyled the proceedings, which otherwiſe might in a little time have produced the 500 <hi>l.</hi> depoſited in the Goldſmiths hand, and full intelligence of the parties concerned in the project, and of the Depoſitions which the Captain was to have Sworn, when he received the 500 <hi>l.</hi> from <hi>Ruſſel,</hi> and the ſeizure of the ſaid <hi>Ruſſel,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Upon <hi>Thurſday</hi> the 23d, of <hi>January,</hi> Mr. <hi>B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ooks</hi> met with the Captain, and told him what <hi>Nettervile</hi> had related to him of the buſineſs of Captain <hi>Kelly</hi> in the <hi>Tower;</hi> He told him the ſtory, as you find in his information. And further told the Captain, that he had another Letter, which he was going to carry to Captain <hi>Kelly</hi> in the <hi>Tower;</hi> and <hi>Netter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile</hi> told him the ſaid Mr. <hi>Brooks,</hi> that if Captain <hi>Kelly</hi> did not ſend him the 7 <hi>l.</hi> he
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:48091:6"/> the ſaid <hi>Nettervile</hi> did know enough to turn him out of the <hi>Tower.</hi> I have, ſaith <hi>Brooks,</hi> taken a Copy of this Letter; and the Captain deſired he might ſee it, which he did; &amp; the contents were to ſignifie to Captain <hi>Kelly,</hi> what a fright the ſaid <hi>Nettervile</hi> had been put into by Mr. <hi>Oat<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s</hi> and Mr. <hi>Bedlow,</hi> having been with him. And therefore <hi>Nettervile</hi> deſired Captain <hi>Kelly</hi> to ſend him the 7<hi>l.</hi> to diſcharge him out of that Priſon, leſt worſe ſhould come on it; and upon the Captains reading the Copy of the ſaid Letter, be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> not to be too haſty in delivering that Letter to Capain <hi>Kelly;</hi> but that he would draw up by way of information what he had told him, and goe along with the ſaid Captain to Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon,</hi> and give in the information, and take his advice.</p>
            <p>So that on <hi>Fryday</hi> the 24th of <hi>January,</hi> the Captain and Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> went to Sir <hi>Jo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeph Williamſon,</hi> and gave him the information, and the ſaid Letter wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>h the Copy the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of; Then Sir <hi>Joſeph</hi> told the Captain and Mr. <hi>Brooks,</hi> that the Committee of Lords was going to ſit, and that they ſhould attend at the Council-door, and he would call them in, that they might know their Lordſhips pleaſure, as to the delivery of the Letter to Captain <hi>Kelly,</hi> After debate, their Lordſhips were of opinion. That the Letter ſhould not be delivered, but thought they had ſufficient ground to Seize Captain <hi>Kelly,</hi> and to ſearch his houſe for <hi>Dominick Kelly,</hi> and for papers; in order to which, Sir <hi>Joſeph Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liamſon</hi> was ſent for his Grace the Duke of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> who immediately came to the Council; where the Lords accquained his Grace with the buſineſs, &amp; deſired he would give Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> a Warrant to fetch Capt. <hi>Kelly.</hi> His Grace was pleaſed to ſend for his Secretary, and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered him immediately to draw a Warrant directed to Sir <hi>John Robinſon,</hi> to aſſiſt them with a G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ard, for executing the Warrant, and <hi>Nettervile</hi> was ordered to be brought to the Council that afternoon.</p>
            <p>And ſo the Captain and <hi>Mr. Brooks</hi> accompanied with Sir <hi>William Waller,</hi> went to the <hi>Tower;</hi> and being Guarded by Sir <hi>John Robinſon,</hi> came to Captain <hi>Kellys</hi> houſe, and there his Footboy came to the door; and upon inquiry for his Maſter, the boy replied, he was not within; they ask't him if he knew where he was; the Boy told them no, for he dined abroad: They went into the Houſe, and in the Room where the Lord <hi>Stafford</hi> Lodgeth, they found Captain <hi>Kelly,</hi> and brought him to the Council with what Papers they could find; but <hi>Nettervile</hi> had been examined; and was gone away before, and had confeſſed the ſending the Letters, and Captain <hi>Kellys</hi> being with them in the <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhalſeys, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Captain thereupon was put into the Meſſengers hands, and ordered to be brought before their Lordſhips next morning, and <hi>Nettervile</hi> alſo (who were face to face at the Council-Table).</p>
            <p>Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> denied that he knew this <hi>Dominick Kelly, Nettervile</hi> told him he would not deny ſurely that he was with them at the <hi>Marſhalſeys,</hi> which Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> then confeſſed; ſome of their Lordſhips asked what he did at the <hi>Marſhalſeys?</hi> Captain <hi>Kelly</hi> ſaid, he went to viſit <hi>Mr. Nettervile,</hi> truly ſaid <hi>Nettervile</hi> 'twas kindly done of you, Sir, for I never ſaw or heard of you before, until your Cozen <hi>Dominick Kelly</hi> told me of you and deſired me to ſend a Letter from him to you.</p>
            <p>Capt. <hi>Kelly</hi> after Examination, was committed to a Meſſenger again; but ſoon after he put in bail, and I have heard there was an Order of Council to turn him o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t of his em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment. But whether it be ſo, or no, I know not.</p>
            <p>That <hi>Ruſſel</hi> (upon the <hi>Thurſday</hi> after Mr. <hi>Oats</hi> and Mr. <hi>Bedlow</hi> had been with <hi>Netter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile,</hi> at the priſon) came again to <hi>Nettervile</hi> and inſtead of being apprehended, as <hi>Nettervile</hi>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:48091:7"/> promiſed <hi>Lowman</hi> he ſhould, <hi>Nettervile</hi> gave him notice of the diſcovery, &amp; he went out immediately &amp; ſcaped. And after he was gone, <hi>Nettervile</hi> then told <hi>Lowman</hi> he had been there; they purſued him, and ſaw him take Boat, but could not overtake him. But Mr. <hi>Brooks</hi> had a warrant from Sir <hi>Joſeph Williamſon</hi> to ſearch for him at his hooſe; but his wife told them, that he was at the <hi>French</hi> Ambaſſadors houſe, and had not lain at home in ten or twelve Nights; which the Council being informed of, were very diligent to appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hend him, and offered 20l, to thoſe that could diſcover him:</p>
            <p>This <hi>Ruſſel,</hi> mentioned in the depoſition, is a Rank <hi>Papiſt,</hi> and an <hi>Iriſh</hi>-man, who mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried Madam <hi>Rowſe,</hi> the Dutcheſs of <hi>Portſmouths</hi> Gentlewoman: <hi>Netterevile</hi> and <hi>Brewer</hi> are of the ſame Faction, and are now Priſoners in the <hi>Marſhalſeys.</hi> The deponents, Capt <hi>Bury</hi> and Alderman <hi>Brooks,</hi> are both honeſt Gentlemen, and good Proteſtants; and ſuch. who<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e principles deteſted either to engage in, or conceal ſuch abominable Villany: how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever <hi>Nettervile</hi> was ſo infatuated, as to conceive them fit to be profligated.</p>
            <p>Now Reader, thou haſt ſeen the whole contrivance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and mayeſt eaſily diſcern what intentions of the <hi>Romaniſts</hi> were; what the natural conſequence thereof would have been, I leave to thy own conjuncture, and ſhall only add this true circumſtance, as a farther confir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of their wicked deſign in this matter, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That ſeveral perſons (by them appointed) were a little before this diſcovery at the hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes of ſome <hi>Perſbyterians,</hi> well known in the City of <hi>London,</hi> to pray their charitable contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bution towards the maintenance of Mr. <hi>Oats</hi> and Mr. <hi>Bedlow,</hi> upon this ſpecious, though falſe ſuggeſtion, That His Majeſties allowance was not ſufficient for their incouragement; but the parties to whom they applied themſelves (ſuppoſing their intentions were to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſe their King and Countrey, and to procure Coyn for themſelves), rejected them with checks; and it was well they did; for otherwiſe, who knows what advantage they might have made thereof, in order to the effecting their wicked enterprize?</p>
            <p>And thus I have done, truſting to the Readers candor, which if a Proteſtant, I do not doubt of; if a <hi>Papiſt,</hi> neither expect or care for it; I being one of quite different princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, and one whoſe prayers, as well as endeavours, ſhall be conſtantly engaged, for the fruſtration of their helliſh Attempts.</p>
            <p>Concerning my intentions in the publication of theſe Depoſitions, they were only for the publick good, and to expoſe to view the wicked ſubtilties of theſe men, that the Nation (and all true Proteſtants) may be made ſenſible of their devices; that if ever they uſe the ſame, or the like again, they may be with the more eaſe detected, and rendred abortive. And alſo that all ſincere Chriſtians, may aſcribe the praiſe of all their deliverances (as well of this as others) to that God who hath ſo viſibly and conſtantly appeared for the vindi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation of his people, and for infatuating the perſons, as well as rendring unſucceſsful the Attempts of his and their implacable Enemies.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:48091:7"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
